

STEVE EARLE

COMPUTER PROGRAMMER AND IT SPECIALIST

CONTACT

6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2

Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3

steve.earle.dev@gmail.com

https://steve-earle.github.io

1-902-219-2072

Steve Earle

[6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2] [Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3] [1-902-219-2072] [steve.earle.dev@gmail.com] [steve-earle.github.io]

Profile

I am a computer science student currently completing my studies at the Nova Scotia Community College Institute of Technology with a focus on object-oriented programming for the development of mobile, desktop, and web applications, as well as full-stack web development. A portfolio of my work can be found at https://steve-earle.github.io

Expertise

Programming

Developing mobile, desktop, and web applications with C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP, and Python

Web Development

Developing websites with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and Laravel

Systems Administration

Maintaining systems such as Linux, Windows, and MacOS

Database Administration

Querying, storing, and editing databases with **SQL**

Version Control/Collaboration

Collaborating and controlling project code with **GitHub**

Project Management

Organizing software development with Scrum/Agile methodologies

Customer Service

Providing clients with professional service in person and via chat/email with years of experience working for large companies as a sub-contractor

Steve Earle

[6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2] [Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3] [1-902-219-2072] [steve.earle.dev@gmail.com] [steve-earle.github.io]

Work Experience

Appen Limited

IT Sub-Contractor

May 2019 – Present

Halifax, Nova Scotia (working remotely)

Responsibilities:

- Management of multiple contracts providing data for machine learning algorithms, search engine evaluation, mapping application analyzation, and social media content accuracy
- Recording and transcription services
- Invoice documentation

GDI Integrated Facility Services

Maintenance Contractor

June 2014 – January 2017

Halifax, Nova Scotia

Responsibilities:

- Management of multiple contracts for building maintenance and cleaning services
- On-site custodial services for offices and warehouse settings

Education

Nova Scotia Community College

IT Programming Diploma

September 2017 – May 2019 (currently attending)

Classes completed:

- Logic and Programming (Python)
- Programming II (C)
- Introduction to Object-Oriented Programming (Java)
- Data Fundamentals (SQL)
- Transactional Database Programming (SQL)
- Operating Systems: Linux
- Introduction to Windows Administration
- Introduction to Networking and Security
- Introduction to Systems Analysis and Design
- User Interface Design and Development
- Website Development (HTML and CSS)
- Advanced Object-Oriented Programming (C#)
- Mobile Application Development for Android (Java and XML)
- Programming C++
- Project Management
- Web Application Programming (PHP)

Steve Earle

[6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2] [Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3] [1-902-219-2072] [steve.earle.dev@gmail.com] [steve-earle.github.io]

Skills

- Motivated problem-solver
- Productive independently or as a member of a team
- Personable communicator
- Easy going and hard working